The	O
human	O
body	O
converts	O
alpha-linolenic	O
acid	O
to	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
.	O
ALA	PERSON
is	O
itself	O
anessential	O
fatty	O
acid	O
,	O
an	O
appropriate	O
supply	O
of	O
which	O
must	O
be	O
ensured	O
.	O
Theefficiency	O
of	O
the	O
conversion	O
of	O
ALA	O
to	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
,	O
however	O
,	O
is	O
much	O
lower	O
than	O
theabsorption	O
of	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
from	O
food	O
containing	O
it	O
.	O
Because	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
is	O
also	O
a	O
precursor	O
todocosahexaenoic	O
acid	O
,	O
ensuring	O
a	O
sufficient	O
level	O
of	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
on	O
a	O
dietcontaining	O
neither	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
nor	O
DHA	ORGANIZATION
is	O
harder	O
both	O
because	O
of	O
the	O
extra	O
metabolicwork	O
required	O
to	O
synthesize	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
and	O
because	O
of	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
to	O
metabolizeinto	O
DHA	ORGANIZATION
.	O
Medical	O
conditions	O
like	O
diabetes	CAUSE_OF_DEATH
or	O
certain	O
allergies	O
maysignificantly	O
limit	O
the	O
human	O
body	O
's	O
capacity	O
for	O
metabolization	O
of	O
EPA	ORGANIZATION
fromALA	O
.	O
