Ellagic	O
acid	O
has	O
been	O
marketed	O
as	O
a	O
dietary	O
supplement	O
with	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
claimedbenefits	O
against	O
cancer	CAUSE_OF_DEATH
,	O
heart	CAUSE_OF_DEATH
disease	CAUSE_OF_DEATH
,	O
and	O
other	O
medical	O
problems	O
.	O
Ellagicacid	PERSON
has	O
been	O
identified	O
by	O
the	O
U.S.	ORGANIZATION
Food	ORGANIZATION
and	ORGANIZATION
Drug	ORGANIZATION
Administration	ORGANIZATION
as	O
a	O
`	O
fakecancer	O
`	O
cure	O
'	O
consumers	O
should	O
avoid	O
'	O
.	O
A	O
number	O
of	O
U.S.-based	MISC
sellers	O
ofdietary	O
supplements	O
have	O
received	O
Warning	O
Letters	O
from	O
the	O
Food	O
and	O
DrugAdministration	O
for	O
promoting	O
ellagic	O
acid	O
with	O
claims	O
that	O
violate	O
the	O
FederalFood	O
,	O
Drug	O
,	O
and	O
Cosmetic	MISC
Act	MISC
.	O
