Ibandronate	O
is	O
indicated	O
for	O
the	O
treatment	O
and	O
prevention	O
of	O
osteoporosis	O
inpost-menopausal	O
women	O
.	O
In	O
May	DATE
2003	DATE
,	O
the	O
U.S.	ORGANIZATION
Food	ORGANIZATION
and	ORGANIZATION
Drug	ORGANIZATION
Administration	ORGANIZATION
approved	O
Ibandronate	PERSON
as	O
a	O
daily	SET
treatment	O
for	O
post-menopausalosteoporosis	O
.	O
The	O
basis	O
for	O
this	O
approval	O
was	O
a	O
three-year	DURATION
,	O
randomized,double-blind	O
,	O
placebo-controlled	O
trial	O
women	O
with	O
post-menopausalosteoporosis	O
.	O
Every	O
participant	O
also	O
received	O
daily	SET
oral	O
doses	O
of	O
calcium	O
and400IUs	O
-LSB-	O
international	O
units	O
-RSB-	O
of	O
vitamin	O
D	O
.	O
At	O
the	O
study	O
's	O
conclusion	O
,	O
bothdoses	O
significantly	O
reduced	O
the	O
occurrence	O
risk	O
of	O
new	O
vertebral	O
fractures	O
by50	O
--	O
52	PERCENT
percent	PERCENT
when	O
compared	O
to	O
the	O
effects	O
of	O
the	O
placebo	O
drug	O
.	O
