Cellcept	O
was	O
developed	O
by	O
a	O
South	NATIONALITY
African	NATIONALITY
geneticist	TITLE
Anthony	PERSON
Allison	PERSON
and	O
hiswife	O
Elsie	PERSON
M.	PERSON
Eugui	PERSON
.	O
In	O
the	DATE
1970s	DATE
while	O
working	O
at	O
the	O
Medical	MISC
ResearchCouncil	MISC
,	O
Allison	PERSON
investigated	O
the	O
biochemical	O
causes	O
of	O
immunune	O
deficiency	O
inchildren	O
.	O
He	O
discovered	O
the	O
metabolic	O
pathway	O
involving	O
an	O
enzyme	O
,	O
inosinemonophosphate	O
dehydrogenase	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
undesirable	O
immuneresponse	O
in	O
autoimmune	O
diseases	CAUSE_OF_DEATH
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
for	O
immune	O
rejection	O
in	O
organtransplantation	O
.	O
He	O
conceived	O
an	O
idea	O
that	O
if	O
a	O
molecule	O
that	O
could	O
block	O
theenzyme	O
is	O
discovered	O
,	O
then	O
,	O
it	O
would	O
become	O
an	O
immunosuppressive	O
drug	O
thatcould	O
be	O
used	O
for	O
autoimmune	O
diseases	CAUSE_OF_DEATH
and	O
in	O
organ	O
transplantation	O
.	O
In	O
1981	DATE
hedecided	O
to	O
go	O
for	O
drug	O
discovery	O
and	O
approached	O
several	O
pharmaceuticalcompanies	O
,	O
which	O
turned	O
him	O
down	O
one	NUMBER
by	O
one	NUMBER
as	O
he	O
had	O
no	O
primary	O
knowledge	O
ondrug	O
research	O
.	O
However	O
,	O
Syntex	ORGANIZATION
liked	O
his	O
plans	O
and	O
asked	O
him	O
to	O
join	O
thecompany	O
with	O
his	O
wife	O
.	O
He	O
became	O
Vice	TITLE
President	TITLE
for	O
the	O
research	O
.	O
In	O
oneof	O
their	O
experiments	O
the	O
Allisons	ORGANIZATION
used	O
an	O
antibacterial	O
compound	O
,	O
mycophenolate	O
mofetil	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
abandoned	O
in	O
clinical	O
use	O
due	O
to	O
its	O
adverseeffects	O
.	O
They	O
discovered	O
that	O
the	O
compound	O
had	O
immunosuppressiveactivity	O
.	O
They	O
synthesised	O
a	O
chemical	O
variant	O
for	O
increased	O
activityand	O
reduced	O
adverse	O
effects	O
.	O
They	O
subsequentlydemonstrated	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
useful	O
in	O
organ	O
transplantation	O
in	O
experimentalrats	O
.	O
After	O
successful	O
clinical	O
trials	O
,	O
the	O
compound	O
was	O
approvedfor	O
use	O
in	O
kidney	O
transplant	O
by	O
the	O
US	ORGANIZATION
Food	ORGANIZATION
and	ORGANIZATION
Drug	ORGANIZATION
Administration	ORGANIZATION
on	O
3	NUMBER
May1995	O
,	O
and	O
was	O
commercialised	O
under	O
the	O
brand	O
name	O
CellCept	O
.	O
