In	O
January	DATE
2006	DATE
P&G	ORGANIZATION
and	O
its	O
marketing	O
partner	O
Sanofi-Aventis	ORGANIZATION
filed	O
a	O
LanhamAct	O
false	O
claims	O
lawsuit	O
against	O
rival	O
drugmakers	O
Roche	ORGANIZATION
and	O
GlaxoSmithKlineclaiming	O
false	O
advertising	O
about	O
Boniva	PERSON
.	O
The	O
manufacturers	O
of	O
Boniva	MEDICINE
,	O
arival	O
bisphosphonate	O
,	O
were	O
accused	O
in	O
the	O
suit	O
of	O
causing	O
a	O
`	O
serious	O
publichealth	O
risk	O
'	O
through	O
misrepresentation	O
of	O
scientific	O
findings	O
.	O
In	O
a	O
ruling	O
onSeptember	O
7	NUMBER
,	O
2006	DATE
U.S.	COUNTRY
District	O
Judge	TITLE
Paul	PERSON
A.	PERSON
Crotty	PERSON
rejected	O
P&G	ORGANIZATION
's	O
attemptedinjunction	O
.	O
P&G	ORGANIZATION
was	O
criticized	O
for	O
attempting	O
to	O
`	O
preserve	O
its	O
market	O
share	O
bydenigrating	O
Boniva	MEDICINE
'	O
.	O
Judge	TITLE
Crotty	PERSON
wrote	O
that	O
`	O
Roche	PERSON
was	O
clearly	O
entitled	O
torespond	O
with	O
its	O
own	O
data	O
,	O
provided	O
that	O
the	O
data	O
was	O
truthfully	O
andaccurately	O
presented	O
'	O
.	O
